Semmler, Alexander; Papers mss131
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Alexander Semmler Papers
1914-1977
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
mss131
10.5 cubic ft.
The Alexander Semmler Papers contain music written by Alexander Semmler, both published and unpublished, as well as some of his notes and correspondence.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
The majority of this collection was donated by Dr. Iliana Semmler in January 2003. David Zimet donated manuscript scores for Opus 32 in 2024.
Biographical Sketch
Alexander Semmler was born in Dortmund, Germany, on 12 November 1900. He began composing music in adolescence and toured Europe and the United States as a pianist at the age of fifteen. He studied piano with Josef Pembaur and composition with Gustav Jenner, and later studied philosophy and musicology at the universities of Marburg, Berlin, and Munich. He emigrated to the United States as a young man and became an American citizen in 1930. Semmler worked as a pianist with the CBS Symphony and later as a staff conductor and composer at CBS, writing music both under his own name and under the pseudonym Ralph Sandor (or Zandor). He served as the American administrator for the Rudfunk im Amerikanischen Sektor (RIAS) in Berlin from 1951 to 1952. He was later invited to Mexico, where he was instrumental in organizing the Centro de Compositores Mexicanos. From 1955 until 1970, he was the New York music director for TRF Music, Inc. and Picture Scores, Inc. During that same time, he served as program director of the Maverick Concerts in Woodstock, N. Y. Semmler died in Kingston, N. Y., on 24 April 1977.
The information provided above was gleaned from the following sources, in addition to those found in the Alexander Semmler Papers themselves:
"Semmler, Alexander." Contemporary American Composers: A Biographical Dictionary. Ed. E. Ruth Anderson. Boston: G. K. Hall, 1982.
"Henry Cowell: Trio for Violin, 'cello, and Piano (1965); Alexander Semmler: Trio for Violin, 'cello, and Piano, Op. 40 (1964)." (see www.newworldrecords.org/uploads/fileuordz.pdf).
Scope and Contents
The collection consists primarily of music written by Alexander Semmler, both in print and in manuscript. Among the compositions are symphonic works, chamber music, and works for various instruments, including piano and voice. There are also sketches for later compositions and notebooks with melodic ideas, both titled and untitled. The papers also include music written by Mr. Semmler under the pseudonym of Ralph Sandor (or Zandor), which is more commercially oriented than those pieces signed in his own name. Much of the music in the collection has never been published.
Also included in the papers are certain items kept with his musical compositions by Alexander Semmler; these miscellanea are noted in the individual series scope notes. Materials are arranged within series either by opus number or alphabetically, if no opus number is present (Series 5 is an exception- please see its scope note for details). Some of the items include emendations tipped in or fastened with tape. Many bear markings or annotations in a hand other than Alexander Semmler's. These were not made by the processing archivist. When these markings included dates, those were included in the folder listing as approximate dates.
It should be noted that while there are multiple copies of most of the items in the Semmler Papers, these copies are often not identical, as many of the manuscripts have corrections or notations by the composer that vary from instance to instance. This is why the archivist elected to retain them. Due to the number of fragile and oversized items in the collection, materials pertaining to the same work may not be housed in the same physical location.
Arrangement of the Collection
The papers are arranged in seven series:
Series 1 - Symphonic Works, 1953, Undated
Series 2 - Works for Piano and Organ, 1941, 1956, Undated
Series 3 - Chamber Music, 1940-1977, Undated
Series 4 - Instrumental Works Without an Opus Number, 1916-1964, Undated
Series 5 - Vocal and Choral Music, 1914-1968, Undated
Series 6 - Works as Ralph Sandor, 1940-1950, Undated
Series 7 - Sketches and Notebooks, 1919-1954, Undated
Materials arranged within series by opus number. Materials without an opus number arranged alphabetically by folder title.
Music; Composers--United States--20th century; Symphonies; Piano music; Organ music; Chamber music; Vocal music; Songs; Incidental music; Radio music; Dance music; Tangos; Amateur films--Songs and music; Jazz; Woodstock (N. Y.); sheet music; Semmler, Alexander, 1900-1977; Pembaur, Josef, 1875-1950; Jenner, Gustav, 1865-1920; Brunetti-Pisano, August, 1870-1943; Knab, Armin, 1881-1951; Herrmann, Bernard, 1911-1975; Lear, Edward, 1812-1888; Machado, Antonio, 1812-1896; Cowell, Henry, 1897-1965; Burnet, Dana, 1888-1962; Castaneda, Daniel Perez, 1901-1980; Columbia Broadcasting System, Inc.; Rundfunk im Amerikanischen Sektor (Berlin, Germany)
- Symphonic Works, 1953; Undated; 1; 1.94 cubic ft.
  Arrangement
  Arranged by opus number.
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of works written by Alexander Semmler for symphony orchestra. The Symphony No. 3, dedicated to RIAS-Berlin, is the longest of these; the title on the full orchestral score is in English, and the parts and corrections are in German, with musical notations in Italian. The other works are all in English, with musical notations in Italian.
  - Opus 18: Sinfonietta (1): To Davidson Taylor (alt. title: Symphony No. 1), Undated; genreform: Bound manuscript score (Oversized 1, Folder 1)
  - Opus 18: Sinfonietta (1): To Davidson Taylor (alt. title: Symphony No. 1), Undated; genreform: Printed parts: Violin 1, Violin 2, Viola, Cello, Bass, Flute 1 and 2, Oboe 1 and 2, Clarinet 1 and 2, Bassoon, Horn 1 and 2, Trumpet 1 and 2, Trombone, and Drums (Box 1 (1-Symphonic Works), Folder 1-8)
  - Opus 20: Manhattan Diary: Impressions and Vignettes for Symphony Orchestra, Undated; genreform: Manuscript score (Oversized 2, Folder 2)
  - Opus 20: Manhattan Diary: Impressions and Vignettes for Symphony Orchestra, Undated; genreform: Onionskin manuscript score (Oversized 2, Folder 3)
  - Opus 21: Second Symphony, Undated; genreform: Manuscript score (Oversized 1, Folder 2)
  - Opus 21: Second Symphony, Undated; genreform: Onionskin manuscript score (Oversized 2, Folder 1)
  - Opus 22: Horizons: A Symphonic Ode, Undated; genreform: Manuscript score (Oversized 2, Folder 4)
  - Opus 22: Horizons: A Symphonic Ode, Undated; genreform: Onionskin manuscript score (Oversized 2, Folder 5)
  - Opus 23: Symphony No. 3: Dedicated to RIAS-Berlin (alt. title: Dritte Simfonie), 1953; genreform: Manuscript score (Oversized 3, Folder 1)
  - Opus 23: Symphony No. 3: Dedicated to RIAS-Berlin (alt. title: Dritte Simfonie), Undated; genreform: Korrekturen (Box 1 (1-Symphonic Works), Folder 9)
  - Opus 23: Symphony No. 3: Dedicated to RIAS-Berlin (alt. title: Dritte Simfonie), Undated; genreform: Printed string parts (Box 1 (1-Symphonic Works), Folder 10-16)
  - Opus 23: Symphony No. 3: Dedicated to RIAS-Berlin (alt. title: Dritte Simfonie), Undated; genreform: Printed non-string parts (Oversized 4, Folder 1)
- Works for Piano and Organ, 1941; 1956; Undated; 2; 1.16 cubic ft.
  This series consists of works written by Alexander Semmler for solo piano and organ. Included in this series is a photocopied clipping of a newspaper review of a concert led by Semmler and featuring one of his works. It is housed with the item to which it was originally attached. All items are in English, with musical notations in Italian.
  - Opus 2: Six Miniatures for Piano Solo, 1941; genreform: Printed score (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Opus 2a: Three Nocturnes for Piano (alt. title: Three Pieces for Piano), Undated; genreform: Manuscript score (Box 1, Folder 18-20)
  - Opus 2a: Three Nocturnes for Piano (alt. title: Three Pieces for Piano), Undated; genreform: Onionskin manuscript score (Oversized 5, Folder 1)
  - Opus 5: First Piano Sonata, Undated; genreform: Manuscript score (Box 1, Folder 21-22)
  - Opus 5: First Piano Sonata, Undated; genreform: Onionskin manuscript score (Oversized 5, Folder 2)
  - Opus 6: Scherzo (for Piano), Undated; genreform: Manuscript score (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Opus 6: Scherzo (for Piano), Undated; genreform: Onionskin manuscript score (Oversized 5, Folder 3)
  - Opus 7: (Twelve) Poems without Words (for Piano), Undated; genreform: Manuscript scores; partial manuscript score (Box 1, Folder 24-27)
  - Opus 7: (Twelve) Poems without Words (for Piano), Undated; genreform: Onionskin manuscript score (Oversized 5, Folder 4)
  - Opus 9: (Second) Suite for Piano (Hommage a Prokofieff) (: March), Undated; genreform: Manuscript score (Box 1, Folder 28-29)
  - Opus 9: (Second) Suite for Piano (Hommage a Prokofieff) (: March), Undated; genreform: Onionskin manuscript score (Oversized 5, Folder 5)
  - Opus 11: Sonata for Piano (alt. title: Second Piano Sonata), Undated; genreform: Manuscript score (Box 1, Folder 30-33)
  - Opus 11: Sonata for Piano (alt. title: Second Piano Sonata), Undated; genreform: Onionskin manuscript score (Oversized 5, Folder 6)
  - Opus 12: Third Piano Sonata (alt. title: Piano Sonata No. 3), Undated; genreform: Manuscript score (Box 1, Folder 34-35)
  - Opus 12: Third Piano Sonata (alt. title: Piano Sonata No. 3), Undated; genreform: Onionskin manuscript score (Oversized 5, Folder 7)
  - Opus 20: Manhattan Diary: Moods and Impressions for Piano, Undated; genreform: Manuscript score (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Opus 20: Manhattan Diary: Moods and Impressions for Piano, Undated; genreform: Onionskin manuscript score (Oversized 5, Folder 8)
  - Opus 27: Four Old Dances in New Style for Harpsichord or Piano, Undated; genreform: Manuscript score (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Opus 27: Four Old Dances in New Style for Harpsichord or Piano, Undated; genreform: Onionskin manuscript score (Oversized 5, Folder 9)
  - Opus 31: Three Sonatinas for Piano, 1956; genreform: Manuscript score (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Opus 31: Three Sonatinas for Piano, Undated; genreform: Onionskin manuscript score (Oversized 5, Folder 10)
  - Opus 32: Musical Notebook: For Nikky: Part One, Volumes 1 to 4, 1956; genreform: Manuscript score (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Opus 32: Musical Notebook: For Nikky: Part One, Volumes 1 to 4, 1956; genreform: Onionskin manuscript score (Oversized 5, Folder 11)
  - Opus 32: Musical Notebook: For Nikky: Part One (Augmented), Undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Opus 32: Musical Notebook: For Nikky: Part One (Augmented), Undated; genreform: Onionskin manuscript score (Oversized 5, Folder 12)
  - Opus 32: Musical Notebook: For Nikky: Part Two, Volumes 5 to 8, 1956; genreform: Manuscript score (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Opus 32: Musical Notebook: For Nikky: Part Two, Volumes 5 to 8, 1956; genreform: Onionskin manuscript score (Oversized 5, Folder 13)
  - Opus 38: The Challenge: Fantasy for Organ, Undated; genreform: Manuscript score (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Opus 38: The Challenge: Fantasy for Organ, Undated; genreform: Onionskin manuscript score (Oversized 5, Folder 14)
  - Opus 41: Five Preludes and Fugues for Piano, Undated; genreform: Manuscript score (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Opus 41: Five Preludes and Fugues for Piano, Undated; genreform: Onionskin manuscript score (Oversized 5, Folder 15)
  - Opus 42: Eight Two-Part Inventions for Piano, Undated; genreform: Manuscript score (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Opus 42: Eight Two-Part Inventions for Piano, Undated; genreform: Onionskin manuscript score (Oversized 5, Folder 16)
  - Opus 46: Fleeting Moments: Three Pieces for Piano, Undated; genreform: Manuscript score (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Opus 46: Fleeting Moments: Three Pieces for Piano, Undated; genreform: Onionskin manuscript score (Oversized 5, Folder 17)
- Chamber Music, 1940-1977; Undated; 3; 2.98 cubic ft.
  This series consists of works written by Alexander Semmler for string or chamber orchestra and other chamber ensembles, both with and without piano accompaniment. Also included in this series is a program from a memorial concert given for Semmler, which was stored with the materials. Some items have attached descriptions of their genesis and performance history, possibly intended originally as program notes. These descriptions, all typewritten, may or may not be Semmler's work. Please note that the notations for the Opus 15 and the Opus 16 items are in German. This fact, coupled with the items' original housing in a RIAS folder, would suggest that they were created during Semmler's time with RIAS, although this is not a certainty.
  - Program for Alexander Semmler memorial concert, 1977 (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 1)
  - Opus 1: Pastoral Suite for Strings (or String Orchestra), 1940; genreform: Manuscript score (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 2)
  - Opus 1: Pastoral Suite for Strings (or String Orchestra), 1942; genreform: Printed score (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 3)
  - Opus 1: Pastoral Suite for Strings (or String Orchestra), 1942; genreform: Printed 1st violin parts (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 4)
  - Opus 1: Pastoral Suite for Strings (or String Orchestra), 1942; genreform: Printed 2nd violin parts (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 5)
  - Opus 1: Pastoral Suite for Strings (or String Orchestra), 1942; genreform: Printed viola parts (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 6)
  - Opus 1: Pastoral Suite for Strings (or String Orchestra), 1942; genreform: Printed violincello parts (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 7)
  - Opus 1: Pastoral Suite for Strings (or String Orchestra), 1942; genreform: Printed bass parts (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 8)
  - Opus 3: Serenade for String Orchestra, 1945; genreform: Printed score (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 9)
  - Opus 4: Quintet for Wind Instruments (Woodwind Quintet), Undated; genreform: Manuscript full score (Oversized 6, Folder 1)
  - Opus 4: Quintet for Wind Instruments (Woodwind Quintet), Undated; genreform: Onionskin manuscript full score and parts (Oversized 6, Folder 2)
  - Opus 4: Quintet for Wind Instruments (Woodwind Quintet), Undated; genreform: Onionskin manuscript parts (Oversized 6, Folder 3)
  - Opus 8: Aria and Scherzo for Flute and String Orchestra, 1949; genreform: Manuscript score (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 10)
  - Opus 8: Aria and Scherzo for Flute and String Orchestra, Undated; genreform: Manuscript flute part (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 11)
  - Opus 8: Aria and Scherzo for Flute and String Orchestra, Undated; genreform: Manuscript piano score and flute part (Oversized 6, Folder 4)
  - Opus 8: Aria and Scherzo for Flute and String Orchestra, Undated; genreform: Manuscript string parts (Oversized 6, Folder 5)
  - Opus 8: Aria and Scherzo for Flute and String Orchestra, Undated; genreform: Onionskin manuscript score and parts (Oversized 6, Folder 6)
  - Opus 8: Aria and Scherzo for Flute and String Orchestra, Undated; genreform: Onionskin manuscript piano arrangement (Oversized 6, Folder 7)
  - Opus 10: String Quartet No. 1, Undated; genreform: Manuscript 1st and 2nd violin parts (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 12-13)
  - Opus 10: String Quartet No. 1, Undated; genreform: Manuscript viola and cello parts (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 14-15)
  - Opus 10: String Quartet No. 1, Undated; genreform: Manuscript full score (Oversized 6, Folder 8)
  - Opus 10: String Quartet No. 1, Undated; genreform: Onionskin manuscript full score (Oversized 6, Folder 9)
  - Opus 10: String Quartet No. 1, Undated; genreform: Onionskin manuscript parts (Oversized 6, Folder 10)
  - Opus 13: Rhapsodie Elegiaque for Cello and Chamber Orchestra, Undated; genreform: Manuscript string parts (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 16-20)
  - Opus 13: Rhapsodie Elegiaque for Cello and Chamber Orchestra, Undated; genreform: Manuscript woodwind parts (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 21)
  - Opus 13: Rhapsodie Elegiaque for Cello and Chamber Orchestra, Undated; genreform: Manuscript horn part (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 22)
  - Opus 13: Rhapsodie Elegiaque for Cello and Chamber Orchestra, Undated; genreform: Manuscript piano part (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 23)
  - Opus 13: Rhapsodie Elegiaque for Cello and Chamber Orchestra, Undated; genreform: Manuscript full score (Oversized 7, Folder 1)
  - Opus 13: Rhapsodie Elegiaque for Cello and Chamber Orchestra, Undated; genreform: Manuscript piano score (Oversized 7, Folder 2)
  - Opus 13: Rhapsodie Elegiaque for Cello and Chamber Orchestra, Undated; genreform: Manuscript cello part (Oversized 7, Folder 3)
  - Opus 13: Rhapsodie Elegiaque for Cello and Chamber Orchestra, Undated; genreform: Onionskin manuscript full score (Oversized 7, Folder 4)
  - Opus 13: Rhapsodie Elegiaque for Cello and Chamber Orchestra, Undated; genreform: Onionskin manuscript piano score and parts (Oversized 7, Folder 5)
  - Opus 14a: 1) Suite for Flute and Oboe; 2) Diversion for Flute and Oboe, Undated; genreform: Onionskin manuscript score (Oversized 7, Folder 6)
  - Opus 14b: 1) Diversion for Four Clarinets in B-flat; Diversion for Four Horns, Undated; genreform: Manuscript score (Oversized 7, Folder 7)
  - Opus 14b: 1) Diversion for Four Clarinets in B-flat; Diversion for Four Horns, Undated; genreform: Onionskin manuscript score (Oversized 7, Folder 8)
  - Opus 15: Sonata for Violin and Piano, ca. 1951-1952; genreform: Manuscript score and typed notes (Oversized 7, Folder 9)
  - Opus 15: Sonata for Violin and Piano, ca. 1951-1952; genreform: Manuscript piano score, manuscript violin part, and typed notes (Oversized 7, Folder 10)
  - Opus 15: Sonata for Violin and Piano, ca. 1951-1952; genreform: Onionskin manuscript score and parts (Oversized 7, Folder 11)
  - Opus 16: Sonata for Two Solo Violins, ca. 1951-1952; genreform: Manuscript score (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 24)
  - Opus 16: Sonata for Two Solo Violins, ca. 1951-1952; genreform: Manuscript Violine 1 part (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 25)
  - Opus 16: Sonata for Two Solo Violins, ca. 1951-1952; genreform: Manuscript Violine 2 part (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 26)
  - Opus 16: Sonata for Two Solo Violins, ca. 1951-1952; genreform: Onionskin manuscript score and parts (Oversized 8, Folder 1)
  - Opus 17: Concertino for Solo Flute and Solo Oboe with Strings/String Orchestra/String Quartet, 1956; genreform: Manuscript piano reduction (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 27-28)
  - Opus 17: Concertino for Solo Flute and Solo Oboe with Strings/String Orchestra/String Quartet, 1956; genreform: Manuscript full score (Oversized 8, Folder 2)
  - Opus 17: Concertino for Solo Flute and Solo Oboe with Strings/String Orchestra/String Quartet, 1956; genreform: Onionskin manuscript full score (Oversized 8, Folder 3)
  - Opus 17: Concertino for Solo Flute and Solo Oboe with Strings/String Orchestra/String Quartet, 1956; genreform: Onionskin manuscript piano score, flute part, and oboe part (Oversized 8, Folder 4)
  - Opus 17: Concertino for Solo Flute and Solo Oboe with Strings/String Orchestra/String Quartet, Undated; genreform: Manuscript flute part (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 29)
  - Opus 17: Concertino for Solo Flute and Solo Oboe with Strings/String Orchestra/String Quartet, Undated; genreform: Manuscript oboe part (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 30)
  - Opus 19: Four Pieces for Violin Solo, Undated; genreform: Partial manuscript score (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 31)
  - Opus 19: Four Pieces for Violin Solo, Undated; genreform: Onionskin manuscript score and parts (Oversized 8, Folder 5)
  - Opus 20: Three Pieces from Manhattan Diary Arranged for Woodwind Quartet, Undated; genreform: Onionskin manuscript score and parts (Oversized 8, Folder 6)
  - Opus 28: Suite for Cello and Piano, Undated; genreform: Manuscript piano score (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 32)
  - Opus 28: Suite for Cello and Piano, Undated; genreform: Manuscript cello part (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 33)
  - Opus 28: Suite for Cello and Piano, Undated; genreform: Onionskin manuscript score (Oversized 8, Folder 7)
  - Opus 28: Suite for Cello and Piano, Undated; genreform: Partial onionskin manuscript score (Oversized 8, Folder 8)
  - Opus 33: Ode for Violin and Piano, 1964; genreform: Manuscript piano score (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 34)
  - Opus 33: Ode for Violin and Piano, 1964; genreform: Onionskin manuscript piano score and violin part (Oversized 8, Folder 9)
  - Opus 33: Ode for Violin and Piano, Undated; genreform: Manuscript violin part (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 35)
  - Opus 34: Rhapsody for Flute and Piano, Undated; genreform: Manuscript piano score (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 36)
  - Opus 34: Rhapsody for Flute and Piano, Undated; genreform: Manuscript flute part and typed program notes (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 37)
  - Opus 34: Rhapsody for Flute and Piano, Undated; genreform: Onionskin manuscript piano score and flute part (Oversized 8, Folder 10)
  - Opus 35: Sonata for Clarinet or Viola and Piano, 1962; genreform: Manuscript piano score (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 39-39)
  - Opus 35: Sonata for Clarinet or Viola and Piano, 1962; genreform: Onionskin manuscript score and parts (Oversized 8, Folder 11)
  - Opus 35: Sonata for Clarinet or Viola and Piano, Undated; genreform: Manuscript clarinet part (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 40)
  - Opus 35: Sonata for Clarinet or Viola and Piano, Undated; genreform: Manuscript viola part (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 41)
  - Opus 36: Diversions for Viola and Bassoon, 1962; genreform: Manuscript score (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 42)
  - Opus 36: Diversions for Viola and Bassoon, 1962; genreform: Onionskin manuscript score (Oversized 9, Folder 1)
  - Opus 37: Fantasy for Oboe, Violin, Viola, and Cello, 1963; genreform: Manuscript score (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 43-44)
  - Opus 37: Fantasy for Oboe, Violin, Viola, and Cello, 1963; genreform: Onionskin manuscript score and parts (Oversized 9, Folder 2)
  - Opus 37: Fantasy for Oboe, Violin, Viola, and Cello, Undated; genreform: Manuscript parts (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 45)
  - Opus 39: Prelude and Scherzo for Violin, Viola, and Cello, 1964; genreform: Manuscript score (Oversized 9, Folder 3)
  - Opus 39: Prelude and Scherzo for Violin, Viola, and Cello, 1964; genreform: Onionskin manuscript score and parts (Oversized 9, Folder 4)
  - Opus 39: Prelude and Scherzo for Violin, Viola, and Cello, Undated; genreform: Manuscript parts (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 46)
  - Opus 40: Trio for Violin, Cello, and Piano, 1964; genreform: Manuscript full score (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 47-49)
  - Opus 40: Trio for Violin, Cello, and Piano, 1964; genreform: Onionskin manuscript score and parts (Oversized 9, Folder 5)
  - Opus 40: Trio for Violin, Cello, and Piano, Undated; genreform: Manuscript violin and cello parts (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 50)
  - Opus 43: Theme and Variations for Four Bassoons, Undated; genreform: Manuscript score and photocopy (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 51)
  - Opus 43: Theme and Variations for Four Bassoons, Undated; genreform: Onionskin manuscript score and parts (Oversized 9, Folder 6)
  - Opus 44: Elegy HC for String Quartet (in memory of Henry Cowell), Undated; genreform: Manuscript score and typed reflections (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 52)
  - Opus 44: Elegy HC for String Quartet (in memory of Henry Cowell), Undated; genreform: Onionskin manuscript score and parts (Oversized 9, Folder 7)
  - Opus 45: Meditation and Capriccio for Flute and Piano (also arranged for Oboe or Clarinet and Piano), 1964; genreform: Manuscript full score (Box 2 (3-Chamber Music), Folder 53)
  - Opus 45: Meditation and Capriccio for Flute and Piano (also arranged for Oboe or Clarinet and Piano), 1964; genreform: Onionskin manuscript full score and parts (Oversized 9, Folder 8)